

Felix A Torrenegra Gamarra

SENIOR RUBY ON RAILS ENGINEER

Profile

Technology **professional** with an **Engineering Degree** focused on **Computer Engineering** from Universidad del Norte with several years of experience in professional environments.

I'm a **Senior Ruby On Rails engineer** who loves to **share knowledge** with coworkers. Always willing to **give you** the best advice and **receive** constructive **feedback**.

Employment History

Senior Ruby on Rails Engineer, Lone Wolf, Remote

JUNUARY 2023 — PRESENT

As a Senior Ruby on Rails engineer at Lone Wolf, I work on multiple microservices, collaborating with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality software solutions. My responsibilities include designing, developing, and maintaining these services, leveraging my expertise in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Jenkins, Salesforce, Sinatra, Elixir, PostgreSQL, Heroku, and other cutting-edge technologies.

I actively participate in code reviews, providing constructive feedback to peers and mentoring junior developers to promote knowledge sharing and team growth.

Achievements: Since joining Lone Wolf, I have made significant contributions to the development of critical microservices, ensuring their scalability, reliability, and overall performance. I successfully implemented integrations with external systems, including Salesforce, streamlining data synchronization processes and enhancing the user experience.

Technologies used: **Ruby**, **Ruby on Rails**, Jenkins, Salesforce, Sinatra, **Elixir**, **PostgreSQL**, **Heroku**

Software Engineer, BairesDev, Remote, Medellin - Colombia

OCTOBER 2021 — OCTOBER 2022

As a contractor of a life insurance company, I work as a **Full-stack** software **engineer** receiving **requirements** from **PO** and **planning** its execution with the **PM** and taking care of the **development**. We made several **integrations** with **external services** and made several **optimizations** making changes from operational management up to systemic topics.

I received a no-production application, and now this application is working as expected and sold its first policies. And we're expecting sell more policies with our several integrations with new providers.

Technologies used: RoR, VueJS, Vue3, Tailwind CSS, Capybara, Rspec, Jtest, Sidekiq, Redis, Active-admin, Storybook

Details

Colombia +57 (305) 796 8758 f.torrenegrag@gmail.com

Links

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u>

Skills

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

PostgreSQL

MySQL

RSpec

Sidekiq

Redis

VueJS

Vue3

Capybara

Jtest

AngularJS

JavaScript

Bootstrap

HTML & CSS

AWS

Heroku

Jira

Git

Linux and Mac system.

Web Developer, Live (Lideres Impactando Vidas con Excelencia) - Secretariat of Culture, Heritage, and Tourism of Barranquilla, Remote, Medellin - Colombia

MARCH 2021 — DECEMBER 2022

Leadership the development team in the **current** administrative platforms. Implemented and maintained **best practice** procedures in all areas of work for several programs. Received new ideas for the **stronger administrative platform** in the Secretariat of Culture, Heritage, and Tourism of Barranquilla. Developed and supported new platforms as a **back-end** developer,

We still building a strong **administrative platform** that citizens can use as a **complete virtual platform** for their class arts. Actually, it has approximately **150.000 users** between students, teachers, administrators, and others, and is working since 2017.

<u>Technologies used:</u> Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, AWS S3, ActiveAdmin, AngularJS, Bootstrap.

Mid Web Developer, Teravision Technologies, Remote - Medellin, Colombia

MAY 2021 — OCTOBER 2021

Responsible for working as an **Intermediate Fullstack** developer for Versapay on ARC product. I delivered several optimizations into an old platform in Ruby On Rails, and now this platform works more **effectively**.

Technologies used: **Docker**, **RSpec**, **Cucumber**, **Ruby on Rails**, **JavaScript**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **Jenkins**.

Mid Web Developer , Team International, Remote - Medellín, Colombia

SEPTEMBER 2020 — MAY 2021

Responsible for working as **MID Backend RoR** developer for IndigoAg, optimizing several APIs, making documentation of new features and new technologies to integrate, using several **integrations** with **AWS services**, **Docker**, **Circle CI**, and others.

Backend developer, Koombea, Barranquilla, Colombia

JUNE 2018 — SEPTEMBER 2020

Responsible for working on a range of projects, designing and estimating **RoR backend sides** robust and efficient for websites, and interacting daily with front-end developers, QA, mobile developers, project managers, and technical leads in the company.

Most relevant project: **e-commerce** for a **big furniture company** in Colombia. Now this e-commerce sells in the all principal cities in Colombia and allows to the company **expand** its **horizons**.

Technologies used: Sidekiq, Pundit, JWT, Devise, AASM, ActiveAdmin, Shopify and ActionCable.

Web Developer, Fundacion Carnaval SA - Secretariat of Culture, Heritage, and Tourism of Barranquilla, Barranquilla, Colombia

NOVEMBER 2018 — NOVEMBER 2019

Leadership in the development of a new administrative platform. Implemented and maintained best practice procedures in all areas of work for several programs.

Languages

English

Spanish

We created a strong platform in which citizens can participate from the postulation up to the delivery of results of awards from the Secretariat of Culture, Heritage, and Tourism of Barranquilla.

<u>Technologies used:</u> Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, AWS S3, ActiveAdmin, AngularJS, Bootstrap.

Web Developer, Fundacion Selseh - Secretariat of Culture, Heritage and Tourism of Barranquilla, Barranquilla, Colombia

JANUARY 2017 — NOVEMBER 2020

Leadership the **development team** in the full life cycle of new **administrative platforms**. Implemented and maintained **best practice** procedures in all areas of work for several programs. **Received** new ideas for new administrative platforms. **Developed and supported** new platforms as a **full-stack developer**, by means of AngularJS and RoR. Provided training on how to use the new platforms.

We created a strong **administrative platform** in which citizens can make their postulation and win scholarships in arts into programs of **EDA**, a program of the Secretariat of Culture, Heritage, and Tourism of Barranquilla. Now, this platform allows to citizens see their grades, take quizzes, see documents from a teacher, have virtual classrooms in it, and learn complete remote with their computers and this platform.

<u>Technologies used:</u> Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, AWS S3, ActiveAdmin, AngularJS, Bootstrap.

Web Developer, Universidad del norte, Barranquilla, Colombia

JANUARY 2016 — DECEMBER 2016

Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new educational applications for teachers and teaching them how to use those applications.

- Receiving new ideas for new educational applications
- Developing and supporting those new applications like a Full-stack developer, with AngularJS and RoR
- Teaching how to use new platforms.

Freelance web developer, Barranquilla, Colombia

JANUARY 2015 — DECEMBER 2015

Responsible for participating in the develop of several small applications with **RoR**, and **AngularJS** to natural persons

Education

Engineer's Degree, Computer Engineering, Universidad del Norte, Barranquilla, Colombia

JANUARY 2012 — DECEMBER 2016